#### OPERATIONS MANAGER

Summary

Bi-lingual: Spanish and English. Proven skills in sales, over 15 years in customer service and money management, inspections and weatherization with the City of Houston, logistics operation, purchasing and leasing, import and export, shipping and handling; demonstrated leadership qualities throughout professional experience, computer skills knowledgeable and skilled using variety of office equipment, fast learner, responsible, self-starter and team player. Volunteer as Director of Communications for MIRA USA branch in Houston Texas. \*Professional and mature \*Resourceful \*Self-directed

Highlights

\*Microsoft Office proficiency

\*Time management

\*Strong problem solver

Experience

Operations Manager 03/2015 to 08/2015 Gaf Buildings Materials Corp. Of America Riverside, CA

- Provide regular supervision and on-going training for front office & enabling services staff; including supervision meetings, evaluations, feedback, support, and coaching.
- Assure smooth operations and communication between Intake, Billing, Referrals, Access, and back clinic operations;.
- Investigate system, work flow, and operational problems and make recommendations;.

Assistant Project Supervisor 11/2012 to 12/2014 Cognizant Technology Solutions Burbank, CA

- Supervise 12 employees, assigned work, schedules and payroll.
- Schedule appointments with contractors and request estimates.
- Monitor work perform by employees and contractors.
- Inspect building for quality control of work.
- Purchase supplies and maintain supply records.

Energy Auditor Inspector 10/2010 to 01/2012 Sephora Destin, FL

- Inspect homes and multi-family housing making energy audits for the City of Houston.
- Collected data to improve energy efficiency in homes.
- Make recommendations of work to be performed.
- Check any discrepancies within the home for the program.
- Monitor contractors work after job completion.
- Maintained high stands of customer service and quality control.

Energy Auditor Inspector 01/2011 to 09/2011 Holston Inspections, Inc City, STATE

- Inspect homes and multi-family housing making energy audits for the City of Houston.
- Evaluate home and multi-family housing training.
- Collected data to improve energy efficiency in homes.
- Make recommendations of work to be performed.
- Check any discrepancies within the home for the program.
- Monitor contractors work after job completion.
- Maintained high stands of customer service and quality control.

Energy Auditor Inspector 03/2010 to 09/2010 Project Management Group City, STATE

- Started installing thermal radiant barrier insulation in homes.
- Promoted to the weatherization assistance program making repairs in homes.
- Began inspecting homes for the City of Houston REEP program.
- Collected data to improve energy efficiency in homes.
- Make recommendations of work to be performed.
- Check any discrepancies within the home for the program.
- Monitor contractors work after job completion.
- Maintained high stands of customer service and quality control.

Merchandiser /Sales 08/2006 to 08/2009 Hines Nurseries, Inc City, STATE

• Maintained store appearance with company product.

- Display product properly by size and category.
- Keep track of inventory on hand and salvage product.
- Make signs and keep with price changes.
- Maintained a high standard of company appearance and customer service.

### Medical Collections 03/2005 to 01/2006 Universal Fidelity City, STATE

- Represented Hospitals as a third party billing agent.
- Contacted insurance companies for unpaid and underpaid medical bills, via telephone and mail.
- Used automated dialing system to contact customers and computer to record customer insurance information.
- Maintained high standards of excellent customer service.

# Recovery Agent 01/1995 to 12/2001 Tele Check Services, Inc City, STATE

- Used automated dialing system to contact customers and computer to record customer account information.
- Process collection items such as checks, drafts and coupons presented to banks.
- Consistently met or exceeded departmental quota goals.
- Adviser of Spanish accounts department to dialer system.
- Trained new employees and follow their progress.
- Maintained high standards of excellent customer service.

### Ticket Agent / Customer Service Agent 05/1992 to 10/1994 Trans World Airlines City, STATE

- Compiled and recorded security information to assemble airline tickets for transmittal to passenger destinations.
- Assisted passengers and checked flight tickets at entrance gate when boarding or disembarking from commercial airplane.
- Maintained high standards of excellence customer service.

# Marketing Merchandiser 10/1992 to 06/1994 National Marketing Services City, STATE

- Marketed and display merchandise for several manufactures for promotion and sales.
- Maintained manufactures merchandise on aisles, end caps and inventory of stock at Toys R Us stores.

# Logistics Operations 11/1989 to 12/1991 Pan American World Airways City, STATE

- Inspected safety precautions labels for import and export of hazardous materials.
- Verified documents of aircraft parts purchase borrowed or loaned from other airlines vendors.
- Oversaw inventory, stocking and distribution of aircraft parts to other hangars and other airport facilities.
- Maintained a high level of excellence in safety.
- Maintained high standards of excellence customer service.

### Education

Information Systems / Business Management 1991 Queens Borough Community College City, State

Information Systems / Business Management

 $\label{thm:lightschool} \mbox{ High School City , State Skills} \mbox{ High School City } \mbox{ High School City$ 

Strong Management and Customer Service Skills, Creative Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Multi-Task Management, Data entry, Documentation, Scheduling and Research.